CLARA DIAS

London, UK +447531581759 claradias.ux@gmail.com claradias.com

USER EXPERIENCE DESIGNER

Problem solver that is passionate about sustainability, human centered design and prioritizing peoples' needs. Bringing previous experience in the healthcare and fine art areas, to offer high attention to detail and empathy into intuitive and engaging user experiences.

UX SKILLS

User Surveys
User Interviews
Statistics & Data Analysis
Competitive Analysis
User Personas
Information Architecture
Paper Prototyping
Wireframing
Usability Testing
Prototyping

TOOLS

Slack Sketch InVision Balsamiq Dropbox

LANGUAGES

English Portuguese

EDUCATION

UX Design

Career Foundry - Germany **2019**

BA (Hons) Fine Arts Painting

Wimbledon College of Arts (UAL) - UK **2017**

BSc Nursing

Escola Superior Enfermagem Coimbra – Portugal **2006**

WORK EXPERIENCE

Visual Artist | Freelance | Sep 2014 - Present

- Multiples exhibitions in Italy, Portugal and UK
- Winner of Prunella Clough Painting Scholarship and SPACE Patrons and Friends Studio Bursary, as well nominated for several painting prizes in UK

Art Technician | The Petchey Academy | Mar 2018 - Present

- Mentoring and 1:1 support to students in lessons/exams
- Technical assistance and demonstration of the use of relevant techniques, mediums and equipment to students and staff
- Assist teachers in the lessons' preparation
- Establishing strong relationships with material suppliers, outreach organizations, galleries and their educational programs
- Managing budget and ordering materials and maintaining equipment, facilities and health and safety guidelines in the art department

Front of House Administrator | SPACE Studios | Mar 2018 – Present

- Managing and supporting gallery visitors, artists, organizations and staff

Artist Assistant | Freelance | May 2015 – Present

- Assisting artists with materials, preparing and production of artworks for commissions and national and international exhibitions

Register Nurse | University College London Hospitals - UK | Nov 2011 – Feb 2018 Register Nurse | Centro Hospitalar Psquiatrico Lisboa - Portugal | Dec 2007 – Nov 2011

Register Nurse | Centro de Saude Santo Condestavel Lisboa - Portugal | Sep 2006 - Dec 2007

- Providing all aspects of nursing care from children to the elderly and their families
- Maintaining high standards of both nursing, medical and surgical care and facilitating effective communication flows between all members of the multi-disciplinary healthcare team. Additionally, providing support and guidance to more junior colleagues, as well as formally mentoring junior staff
- Reinforcing the implementation of mental health programs and the social integration of mental health patients in the community

Guest Link Nurse | Universidade de Cabo Verde (UniCV) – Cape Vert Islands | July 2010 – July 2010

- Mentoring and 1:1 support to eight students in their surgical placement in the national hospital
- Monitored, analysed and assessed the learning progress of the students
- Collaborated with the course leaders in the structure of the BSc Nursing coursework